A Guide to the Washington Times: "The Civil War", 1996-2005
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Washington Times: "The Civil War" 1996-2005
Thomas Balch Library
M 035
1 cu. ft.
The Washington Times newspaper's "The Civil War" articles, spanning from July 6, 1996, to October 29, 2005. Each supplement is published on a single page containing one to three articles.
John O'Brien
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research
Acquisition Information
John O'Brien, Charles Town, WVA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2005.0230
Biographical Information
The Washington Times newspaper was established in 1982, and quickly became a widely-circulated publication. It has been read and lauded by many important political officials in Washington, including former presidents, and refers to itself as "America's Newspaper."
The Times began its "The Civil War" series in 1991. It has had a number of frequent contributors, including John Hunt Morgan Roberts (d. 1999). After more than a decade, the supplement continues to be published today.
Scope and Content
"The Civil War" newspaper articles span from July 6, 1996, to October 29, 2005. Each supplement is published on a single page containing one to three articles. The collection is in excellent condition.
The series is particularly concerned with anecdotes from Civil War soldiers, generals, and battles. However, it also takes note of battlefields and other period historical sites that are currently vulnerable to encroaching development. It contains notices of upcoming events, including battlefield commemorations and Civil War conferences in Virginia, Maryland, Pennsylvania, and the District of Columbia. The series also includes Civil War book reviews, as well as articles concerning the medical, industrial, and technological advances that helped shape the war and its outcome.
The Civil War articles are the only items in this collection.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
The Washington Times, www.americasnewspaper.com/ME2/Default.asp
Other Finding Aid
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - "Love Conquers All As Union's Trap for Mosby Fails," "'Corruption' Tag Misapplied to Grant," n.d.
  - "Island Prison Haunted by History, Perhaps More," "Restoration Returns Look of 1860s to Fort," "New Exhibit in Richmond Rounds Out Image of Lee," n.d.
  - "Governor's Sly Tactics Keep Maryland in Union," "Thomas Holliday Hicks Notes Peril Facing State," n.d.
  - "Lieber Code Sets Ground Rules for Waging War," "Poem Hails Bravery of Female Color Bearer," n.d.
  - "Battlefield Tours Bring Kin Closer to 'Col. Sam'," n.d.
  - "Rebel Scout: Hero, Murderer or Turncoat?," "Thanksgiving Observed in Mist of War," n.d.
  - "Lee's Action at Antietam Part of Master Plan," n.d.
  - "'Spoon River' Poet Reviled for Kicking Lincoln's Pedestal," "Forum Preserves Legacy of 16th President," "Group Helps Scholars, Enthusiasts Better Understand His Historical Impact," n.d.
  - "History Owes Debt to 'Pack Rat' General Willcox," "Actions of Kearny, Stevens Save Army," n.d.
  - "Lessons of Gettysburg Not Lost on Churchill," "Baptism of Fire Came Early for Class of '61," n.d.
  - "Lanesville Summit is Open to the Public," "7th Regiment's First-Rate Defense of Capital," n.d.
  - "Memoirist's Affection, Sympathy Set Work Apart," "Authors Remove Tarnish Heaped on Lee," n.d.
  - "Battlefield Dispatches Bring Conflict Home," "Blue Gray Black White," "Mountaineer's Warning Saves Railroad," n.d.
  - "New War Stirs Reunited Troops of Confederacy," "Lee, Flaws and Genius: Clear View of Man, His Generals," n.d.
  - "An Alliance between Two Giants," "Front Royal Recalls the Brutal Killings of Mosby's Men," n.d.
  - "Nation's Bondage to Slavery Issue Led to Conflict," "Semmes Made Legend of Confederate 'Raiders,'" n.d.
  - "Economics, Culture Behind North-South Split," "Fairfax Encounter with Mosby Shames Union," n.d.
  - "Soldiers Paintings Capture the Drama of Conflict," "History of Taps Echoes through Arlington Exhibit," n.d.
  - "For Two Generals, Bible as Mighty as the Sword," "Southern Ties\Hurt Priest, College He Led," n.d.
  - "Concerts, Recording Replay Era's Songs," "Hanover Battle a Prelude to Gettysburg," "War Comes to Pittsburgh in Arsenal Explosions, Death," n.d.
  - "Baileys Face-Off an Early Proof of Officers' Mettle," "Love Story Told in Captive Captain's Diary," n.d.
  - "No Happy Ending for Actress Who Spied," "Steamboat Horror Goes Unnoticed," "Madman's Gift to the English Language," n.d.
  - "Chamberlain Book Shows Man Behind the Myth," "Duke's Reign of Success with Morgan's Raiders," n.d.
  - "Portraits of Lincoln Show Ravages of His Struggle," n.d.
  - "Did Meade Miss Chance to Destroy Lee's Army?," "Longstreet Blameless for Gettysburg Loss," n.d.
  - "Battle of Hagerstown Bought Lee Some Time," "Declaration was Core of Lincoln's Thought," n.d.
  - "Analyzing Lee's Decision to Order Pickett's Charge," n.d.
  - "Today's Technology Finds 1863 Confederate Dead," n.d.
  - "Writer Roberts Lived Life to Fullest," "War Decimates Best Units Both Sides Have to Offer," n.d.
  - "Director of Secret Service for Lincoln," "Diary a'you are there' Small-town Chronicle," n.d.
  - "When Hallowed Grounds Succumb to Indifference," n.d.
  - "Soldiers' Poetry Recounts Wartime, Postwar Travails," "Journalists' Monument Needs Editing," n.d.
  - "War's Outbreak Leads Clergy to Leave Pulpit, Answer Call to Arms," "Book Traces Union's Revolving-Door Leadership," n.d.
  - "South Saves Aiken Only to Lose Columbia," "Johnson Impeachment Saga Revisited," n.d.
  - "Book Vividly Frees Artillerymen from Obscurity," "A Soldier's Account of Near-Fatal Wound," n.d.
  - "Final Book on Lincoln Not Yet Written," "Civil War Musical Should Surrender," n.d.
  - "The Union's Response to Fort Sumter," "Confederate Turns into Advocate for Black Civil Rights," "Douglass Wilson's Book Wins 1999 Lincoln Prize," n.d.
  - "Battle Over Salt Leads to Atrocities," "Tactics of Daring Raider Get Close Look," "Trent Affair Almost Starts U.S.-British War," n.d.
  - "Feds and Rebs Were United in their Love of Baseball," n.d.
  - "Loyal Mascots Followed Maters into Conflict," "War Sparked Success for 3 Songwriters," n.d.
  - "Oceanographer's Life an Erratic, Creative Voyage," n.d.
  - "Union Troops Train in Arlington for Bloody Campaign," "Cameron: Anything but a Straight Track," n.d.
  - "Farmer's Carvings on Cane Recall a Special Guest," "History of Union Navy is too Shallow," n.d.
  - "Union Invasion Interrupts Governor's Inauguration," "Captivating Melody 'Lorena' Remains a Favorite," n.d.
  - "Abraham Lincoln's Great Laws of Truth, Integrity," "Rebels Make a One-Track Mind Work for Them," n.d.
  - "Adultery, Bloodshed and 'Trial of the Century,'" "'Peace Mission' Fails as Lee's Fortunes Turn," n.d.
  - "1864 Would Prove Pivotal to Conflict's Outcome," "Davis Used Creative Tack at Court-Martial," n.d.
  - "Adventurous Life of Founder of the Irish Brigade," "'Stonewall's Gold' a Priceless Novel," n.d.
  - "Reconstruction, Impeachment Through Gallic Eyes," n.d.
  - "Newspaperman Fought Hard to Serve in Military," "Lincoln Could Have Prevented the War," n.d.
  - "Machine Guns: Old but Deadly Wartime Inventions," "Rebels were Losers in Phony Money Game," n.d.
  - "Romantic Mysteries of a New England Nurse," "Executed Soldiers Served in 'Different Way,'" n.d.
  - "How Two Siblings Sacrificed Themselves," "Federals Lost Chance to Win at Fredericksburg," n.d.
  - "Horror on the Way to 'Helmira' Prison," "Records of Confederate Burials Saved by Ex-Slave," n.d.
  - "Novel year-2000 Woes as Confederacy Rules," "South's Defeat at Gettysburg Follows Frustration at Bridge," n.d.
  - "Historian Raps Jefferson in his Gettysburg Address," "War Movie May Be Filmed in Maryland," "Ward Used Potomac as 'Moat' to Protect Imperiled Capital," n.d.
  - "'The Other Custer' Covered Himself with Valor," "La. Center Preserves War's Record, History," n.d.
  - "Richmond Bank Gold Lost Despite Transfer," "Swamp Dragons Muddy the Way of Rebel Raiders," "Unconvincing, Cliché-ridden'Dahlgren Affair,'" n.d.
  - "Rosecrans Remains Unsung Strategic 'Genius,'" n.d.
  - "Author Strikes Gold in Tale of Struggle for Plains," "Playwrite Finds Battle's Emotion Elusive," n.d.
  - "Similar Rebel Beginnings, Radically Different Endings," "Absorbing, Fresh Letters of a Union Officer," n.d.
  - "Book Proves a True Testament to D.C. Monuments," "Rebels Thwart Union Threat to Richmond," n.d.
  - "'Sticking Out Like a 'Sore Thumb' Costs General a Leg," "Union's Porter Floats Bogus Boat to Sink his Enemy," "Lee Loses Fight to Regain Ground North of James," n.d.
  - "Grant's Third Campaign North of James River Sinks," "Alexander Stephens: Confederate Paradox," n.d.
  - "Flawed Look at How Artists Painted the Conflict," n.d.
  - "Memorial Honors Black Troops," "Sharpsburg of 1862, Antietam Come Alive Again," n.d.
  - "Grant Crosses James River to Force Lee's Hand," "Pennypacker Proved His Mettle Early On," n.d.
  - "Story of 'Irish Rebels' Reflects Character of Conflict," "Governor at Odds with his State," n.d.
  - "Red Tide of Casualties Flowed into Chimborazo," "The Captured-by-Yankees Train that Couldn't," n.d.
  - "British Attitudes Toward Conflict Shaped by Class," "Raiders Net Teen Recruit, Supplies, Booze," n.d.
  - "Loudoun Rangers Wage Lonely Fight for Union," "A Disastrous Bluff for Union Forces," n.d.
  - "Slow to Accept Defeat, Texas Fought Reconstruction," "When Green Armies Collided, Red Blood Flowed," n.d.
  - "One Rebel's Dramatic, Unsentimental Memoirs," " Surviving on Barest of Staples," n.d.
  - "Eerie Similarities Between Gettysburg, Crimean Charges," "Monument Feat: Gettysburg Tribute to 'Ole Pete,'" n.d.
  - "Conflicts Compared to Find First 'Total War,'" n.d.
  - "Henry Stanley's Life as Soldier, Famous Explorer," "Memories of War Found in the 'Attic,'" n.d.
  - "The Glories and Agonies of 'Lee's Miserables,'" "Nude Rebels Turn Back Cavalry at Bridge," n.d.
  - "Surliness Snarls Career of General 'Grumble' Jones," "McPherson Wins Lincoln Prize," "General Frank Blair was both Patriotic and Errant," n.d.
  - "General's Role Brings Indian Bloodshed, Land Loss," "Two-sniper Theory Tied to Kearny's Death," n.d.
  - "War Marked Start of the Era of Big Government," "Georgia's Road to Succession Led to a Bitter and War-Torn Dead End," n.d.
  - "Defeat of 'Slavocrats' Part of Marx's World Vision," n.d.
  - "Portable Hemp bales Turned Tide in Missouri," n.d.
  - "Warriors for Religion Enlist Troops on Both Sides," "Battles Without Noise Baffle Soldiers," n.d.
  - "Belated Salute to Winfield Scott, 'First Truly Professional Soldier,'" "Model 1842 Smoothbore both Reliable and Accurate," "Vicksburg Canal Projects Become Deadly Debacles," n.d.
  - "A Pastor's Riveting, 79-Page Account of Siege," "Smithsonian Tires to Play Neutral Role," n.d.
  - "Hunt for One Grave Yields Records on 520," "'Lack of Will' Theory Takes a Beating," n.d.
  - "An Early and Influential Advocate of Secession", "Daring Rebel Sea Raid Came Too Late," n.d.
  - "Florida Soldiers Served in Wars of U.S., Egypt," "Don Fehrenbacher Wins $50,000 Lincoln Prize," n.d.
  - "Arms Race that had Major Impact on the War: Legendary Colt Pistols," n.d.
  - "Ship Bell Rings in Legal History," "Uniforms Not Very Uniform in Battle," "Skirmishes Shoot for Authenticity in Using Live Ammunition from Era," n.d.
  - "Rebels Made Burning Springs Live Up to its Name," "Soldiers' Christmas: Suffering Revelry," n.d.
  - "The Remarkable Life, Career of William Oates," "Quantrill Left Bloody Tracks on West," n.d.
  - "Heroics, Myth of 'Johnny Shiloh,'" "True Colors of Confederate Flags," "Long, Difficult Birth of Maryland's Banner," n.d.
- (Box 2)
  - "Precedents for Military Tribunal Date to 1846," n.d.
  - "Rebel General Smitten by Va. Beauty's Charm," "Author's Baby-Boomer Bleating Mars 'Lincoln's Elegy,'" n.d.
  - "General's Bravery Brings Him Fame, Injury," "Museum Stands Near Attack Site," "Authors Inflate Role of Loudoun's Wives," n.d.
  - "Civil Rights an Early Casualty," "Visits to Camp Break Loneliness of Soldiers' Wives," n.d.
  - "Haze of History Envelopes Pickett's 2nd Wife, Son," n.d.
  - "Iron Ring of Occupation Stifles Alexandria," "Lee as 19th Century's Washington: Overstated," n.d.
  - "Tiny Smoketown Bears Aftermath of Antietam," "Surrender Temporary for Many in South," n.d.
  - "Music Central to Both Sides' War Efforts," "A Rebel Plot and Germ Warfare," n.d.
  - "Did South Authorize a 'Hit' on Lincoln," "Lee's Shadow Betrays His Plans," n.d.
  - "Little-Known Battle where 'Jeb' Stuart Died," n.d.
  - "Sickness, Death at Andersonville Await Ohioans Taken After Skirmish," "Hearing is Believing on Field of Battle," n.d.
  - "Lincoln's Steadfast Secretary of State," n.d.
  - "Exploits of a 'Grey Ghost' from Maryland," "How a 'Grand Havoc' Kept Kentucky Out of Confederacy," n.d.
  - "Navy Hospital Witness to Hubbub, History," "Faith Motivated Men's Bravery in Battle," n.d.
  - "Adventure, Romance Around Mosby's Rock," "Hollywood's Always Changing 'Reel War,'" n.d.
  - "Antietam Proves Another Folly for McClellan," "Mules Tough and Useful to North and South," n.d.
  - "Price on Her Head No Deterrent to 'Conductor' Tubman," "Diplomatic War Over Rebel Ships," n.d.
  - "Southern Guerilla Wearing a Petticoat," "Captain Sally Saves Rebel Injured," n.d.
  - "Valor of Southern Soldiers Not Forgotten," n.d.
  - "Virginia Railroads Vital to the Southern Cause," "An Amazing Branch of the Confederacy," n.d.
  - "Camel Corps a Unique Band of Recruits," "A Comprehensive but Concise History," n.d.
  - "Controversy, Heroism, Failure at Gettysburg," n.d.
  - "Remember the 19th Maine and Its Heroism," "Author's Short Career as a Wartime Nurse," n.d.
  - "The Military Voyage of Ulysses," "'Black Terror' Ship Fools Rebel Forces Protecting Vicksburg," n.d.
  - "William Mahone: A 5-foot-1 Rebel 'Every Inch a Soldier,'" "Ga., Gettysburg Prove Officer's Mettle," n.d.
  - "Fitzhugh Lee a Major General in Two Armies," "Bloody Battles Leave Soil Rich for Literature," n.d.
  - "Words that Doomed Stonewall Jackson," n.d.
  - "Legally, Mystique of Stonewall Jackson," "Crossroads: Vital Link in Local History," n.d.
  - "Two Founders of Confederacy Help Weaken It," "Creative Tactics of a Union Officer," n.d.
  - "Clearer View of Hero's Military, Political Careers," "Capturing Rebel Ship, International Flack," n.d.
  - "William H. Seward's Brush with Assassination," "A Great Idea Turns into a Poor Novel," n.d.
  - "Tennessee Fight New Battle of Spring Hill," "1864 Clash Leaves Enduring Stain on Hood," n.d.
  - "Douglass a Witness to Lincoln's Conflicting Sides," "Lincoln Exalted but Still Controversial," n.d.
  - "Irishman in Confederate Gray Also Foe of Slavery," "'Jeff in Petticoats' Kicks Rebel President," n.d.
  - "Sale of Pardons Taints Johnson's Presidency," "Lincoln Prize Goes to Russell Weigley," "Fight to Save Three Virginia Battlefields," n.d.
  - "Rebels Shatter Union Force in Charlestown Rout," "Why South Lost War: the Enemy Within," n.d.
  - "Brotherhood 'Army' Invades Canada in 1866," " Neglected Pages Show Conflict as it was Imagined," n.d.
  - "The Prussian who Designed Stars and Bars," "Quartermaster's Behind-Scenes Heroics," n.d.
  - "Troy Cadets Continue to Uphold Tradition," "Exploits of a Confederate Scout," n.d.
  - "Train of Wounded Troops Pulled by Black Soldiers," n.d.
  - "'Odyssey': Soldier's Memoir of War and Agony," "Forgotten Soldier Carved Name in History," n.d.
  - "Union Train Raid Becomes Untracked," "Old John Burns of Gettysburg," "Calvary Clash Leaves Mark on Small Town," n.d.
  - "Ceremony in England Honor Southern Patriots," "Superficial Assessment of Robert E. Lee," n.d.
  - "Army Engineers' Brawn, Brains Support Troops," "Judah Benjamin's Unique Political Career," n.d.
  - "Union Signal Corps' Vital Role at Gettysburg," "Falls Church History Filled with Legends," n.d.
  - "Naval Showdown Catches Eye of Europe," "Finding the Truth About 'Lost Cause,'" n.d.
  - "Comic-Opera 'Duel' Foretells Bloodier Fight," "North Punishes Lee for Siding with South," n.d.
  - "Aldie Witnesses Small but Fierce Engagement," "Barrage of Books Target Christmas Shoppers," n.d.
  - "A Neurologist's Wartime Medical Breakthroughs," n.d.
  - "Book Gangs Up on Myths About James Brothers," "Evolution of Military Staffs During War," n.d.
  - "Former Adversaries Serve Side by Side on Court," "'Battle Hymn' Author, Husband Fight a Long Battle Called Marriage," n.d.
  - "From Soldier to Justices: Holmes Fought for the Union," "While Lurton Sided with the Confederacy," n.d.
  - "Four Novels that Don't Make History a Casualty," "Grant Victorious as Historical Fiction," n.d.
  - "Stone Becomes Fall Guy After Ball's Bluff Fiasco," "Tale About Rebel Sea Raider is a Great Read," n.d.
  - "Gen. Hood Unlucky in Battle, Unlucky in Love," n.d.
  - "A 'Wild Rose' and her Confederate Spy Ring," "Cabin a Time-Worn Survivor of Bloodbath," n.d.
  - "Actress's Domestic Conflict Doesn't Make a War," "Sherman's March Away from High Office," n.d.
  - "Ground of Antietam Farm Turns Red," "A Thorough Study of Atlantic Campaign," n.d.
  - "Napoleon's Shadow Over American Warriors," "Vermont Raid Creates International Incident," n.d.
  - "Hungry Irish Join North's Fight Against South," "Chickamauga Retreat Ends Negley's Career," n.d.
  - "A Sea Change Under Dahlgren," "Priest Devils His Archbishop by Advocating Equal Rights," n.d.
  - "In-Depth Study of Generals' Military Acumen," "S.C. Capital Tower Rises Only on Rebel Bills," n.d.
  - "Davis Passes Up Chance to Buy Navy Early in War," "Monitor Ushered in the 'Reign of Iron,'" n.d.
  - "Sharpshooters Change Way Battles are Waged," "Williamsport: Caught in Middle of War," n.d.
  - "Conflict Leaves Poet Whitman a Better Man," "Abolitionist Lovejoy Loses Life to Cause," n.d.
  - "Secession's Apologists Gut Constitution, History," n.d.
  - "Lincoln's 1864 Victory was Closer than It Looked," "Frontier Legend Fremont Fails as General," n.d.
  - "Anaconda Plan Puts Fatal Squeeze on the South," "Songs, Poems of War Mostly Forgotten," n.d.
  - "Wallace's Delaying Action at River Makes Early too Late," n.d.
  - "Crucial Campaigns Along the Mississippi," n.d.
  - "Battle at Chancellorsville Raises Many 'What-ifs,'" "Devil or God? Filmmakers' Lee is Neither," n.d.
  - "Thirty Young Girls Perish in Factory Flames," "Spy Mission Ends Fatally for Local Rebel," n.d.
  - "How Cold Harbor Became Grant's Waterloo," "Telegraph Transforms News-Writing Style," n.d.
  - "Supreme Court Makes Secession a Lost Legal Cause," "Tyler Finds Confederacy's Cause Just," "Why the South was Right, North Wrong," n.d.
  - "Confederacy Loses Spy to Wartime Romance," "Intriguing But Flawed Study of Antietam," n.d.
  - "Black Officer Gains Almost Mythic Status in Death," "A Young Woman of Quiet Bravery Dies," n.d.
  - "Grant Inspires his Troops with Unrelenting Tactics," "Jefferson Davis and his Fort Sumter Decision," n.d.
  - "A Different Gettysburg Battle," "Lincoln's Ideal of Unity Listed Among the Missing," n.d.
  - "Congress Restore's Lee's Full Citizenship in 1975," "The Feisty 'Brigade' of Wartime Reports," n.d.
  - "General's Exploits Earn Him Fame If Not Success," " Hardships of a Pre-Southern Preacher," n.d.
  - "Honor Among Masons Saves officer from Death," "Tough Colorul Zouaves Help Occupy Alexandria," n.d.
  - "Battle for Hearts and Minds Fought in England," "A Victorious Account of Chambersburg Raid," n.d.
  - "Untangling the Complex Life of Ulysses Grant," "Dranesville Clash Small But Costly in Lives," n.d.
  - "A Fitting and Final Salute to Union Colonel Einstein," "Mason Professor Wins Book Prize," n.d.
  - "Alabama Unit Defies Neighbors for Union," "Lees Win Fight Over an Arlington Horse," "Homestead is a Repository of History," n.d.
  - "Elmira: A Prison of Horror for Confederates," n.d.
  - "At Gettysburg, Battle Went Wrong for Wright," n.d.
  - "'Long Blade' Prussian Came to Fight for the South," "Lincoln Cements Rail-Splitter Image with Campaign Stunt in Illinois," n.d.
  - "Politician-Turned-General Loses Fight with Fellow Officers," "Songs Unify South, Reflect Changing Ideas," n.d.
  - "Veterans Survive War Only to Die in Indian Fight," "A Contrarian View of the Great Emancipator," n.d.
  - "City Takes Repeated Beatings from North and South," "Facts vs. Fictions in Old 'Barbara Frietchie,'" n.d.
  - "Mountain Credo Runs Afoul of Military Justice," n.d.
  - "3 Top Union Officers Lost in Battle of Perryville," "Bonds Shaped by War Can Never Be Buried," n.d.
  - "Industrialization and Its Role in Armed Conflict," "New Books on Warfare," "Davis' Hesitation Nearly Dooms Fight," n.d.
  - "Thomas Shows He's No Slacker in Taking Offensive," "Fictional 'Sojers' Please Veterans, Perhaps Crane," n.d.
  - "Chamber a Capital Symbol of Country's Unity," n.d.
- (Box 3)
  - "Work Scrutinizes Presidents at War," "Collector Forges Link to Past," n.d.
  - "Stories Conflict Over Lincoln's Visit to Antietam," "Iron Brigade Meets Rebels in Bloody Cornfield," n.d.
  - "Lincoln Finds Summers of Respite in Rural Area," "Union Private's Badge of Courage," n.d.
  - "Surrender at Bridge Based on Foe's Word," "Richmond Spinster a Blue Angel," "No Limit to Achievements of 'Extra Billy,'" n.d.
  - "Peaceful Farm Life Interrupted by Battle," "Horrific Face-Off in Spotsylvania," "Scrupulously Researched Look at Chaplains," n.d.
  - "Monitor a Tourist Draw in Washington First," "Frank, Detailed Picture of a Union Soldier's Life," "Slavery, Not States' Rights, Inspired Secession," n.d.
  - "Member Ties Grieving Church to Assassination," "Rebel, Yes, But She a Useful Spy?" n.d.
  - "Hunley Sub Still Holds Mysteries," "Flawed Research Hits Ohio History Marker," n.d.
  - "Western Fights Given More Than Fair Credit," "Lee's Honor Evident After Ox Hill," n.d.
  - "Union Cavalry: From Early Failures to Fame in Film," n.d.
  - "Smart Look at Gettysburg Intelligence," "Society's Colonizing Goals for Liberia," n.d.
  - "Longstreet Becomes Target of Lee's Admirers," "'Labors, Self-Sacrifices' of Nuns Serving as Nurses," n.d.
  - "Pleasonton Slow to Track Lee's Push North," "'Our American Cousin' Survives Lincoln's Assassination at Ford's," n.d.
  - "Bearss an Iconic Force in History Preservation," "Gingrich's Novel Look at Gettysburg," n.d.
  - "Battles Leave an Army of Disabled," "'Herkimer Regiment' Bloodied for Union," n.d.
  - "Cold Harbor's Brave Men Lost in Fierce Rebel Firing," "Porterfield Never Recovers After Philipi," n.d.
  - "Stuart and His Slow March to Gettysburg," "Writers Gild the Legend of Hidden Gold," "Wartime Era of C & O Canal," n.d.
  - "Fort Built, Defended by Blacks Tells of Their Valor," "The Sinking of the CSS Alabama," "Few Writers Found the Right Words to Express North-South Conflict," n.d.
  - "Later Actions Cloud Career of Gettysburg Hero," "Twain Rallies to Rescue of Friend Grant," n.d.
  - "Confederacy's Safe Harbor Ends at Wilmington," "Rebels Fend Off Pursuit After Gettysburg," n.d.
  - "A Fascinating 'Controversy,'" "Family Accounts of Death of Stonewall," n.d.
  - "Scout was Determined Warrior for Rebels, Gold," "Rebel Leaders, Emma, too, Knew Stringfellow's Merit," n.d.
  - "Bucolic W.Va. Region Once Theater of Battles," "Dix's War to Save the Wounded in Hospitals," n.d.
  - "Maryland Memorial Part of Reporter's Legacy," "Immigrants Engineers a Career in Rebel Army," n.d.
  - "Sherman Marches Journalist into Obscurity," "Mrazek's Intriguers Pack Gun Carriages, Beef," "Radio Host Thinks Writer Misfired in Analysis of 'Gods, Generals,'" n.d.
  - "Rail King Dodge a Spy Chief in Vicksburg Fight," "Chaplain's Beliefs Included Rebel Cause," n.d.
  - "'Gods, Generals' Gets History, But is it Truth?" n.d.
  - "Thorough Account of Clash of Cavalries," "Rebel Dead Faced Uncertain Burial," n.d.